microchip.com 2019-05-12

# Privacy Policy | Microchip Technology

Microchip Technology Inc. ( **"Microchip"** ) is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. This Privacy Policy explains how we use the information we collect about you, how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information and the procedures that we have to safeguard your privacy. This Privacy Policy sets out the information requested from you when you access www.microchip.com, www.microchipdirect.com, or sample.microchip.com (the **"Sites"** ).

How is Customer Information Obtained by Microchip and How is it Used?

We receive and store information you give us. Most of the information you give us is collected when you buy products on-line, request literature/ information, participate in a contest, fill out a questionnaire/survey, participate in an on-line discussion, or complete your Customer Profile. You may give us information such as your name, address, phone numbers, e-mail addresses, financial information, employment information, application information, ideas for new projects or applications, and your buying interests. The information that you provide us is used to respond to your requests, notify you of products being shipped to you, customize your interactions with us, improve our offerings, provide materials or offers to you, allow you to participate in contests, and communicate with you. It is your choice whether or not to provide us with certain information. However, you may be unable to take advantage of many of our offers and features if we do not receive your customer information.

We also receive and store certain types of information through use of “cookies.” Some examples of information gathered this way are the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, log-in, e-mail address, password, computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, platform, and the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) used to, through, and from our Sites. We use the information gathered by “cookies” to manage and customize your on-line shopping experience and to improve our offerings.

You may also submit technical information to Microchip such as designs, ideas or data, that you transmit to or post on any of our Sites (the "Submission") for purposes not limited to contest participation. The Submission is considered and treated by Microchip as nonconfidential and nonproprietary. By providing the Submission, you grant Microchip a nonexclusive, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, sublicensable right to disseminate, display, use, modify, copy, adapt, and translate the Submission for any purpose whatsoever, whether commercial or noncommercial, throughout the world in any media. You also grant us the right to use the name you submit in connection with your Submission, if we choose. You represent and warrant in making the Submission that you own or control all rights to the Submission, and that use of your Submission will not cause injury to any person or entity including Microchip. You will indemnify Microchip for all claims resulting from your Submission.

How can I manage the information Microchip has about me?

You can always choose not to give Microchip information. However, certain information is necessary in order for you to take advantage of “microchipdirect”, “sample.microchip”, change notifications, literature updates, etc.

If you want to add/update your information or preferences, please modify your Account Profile. When you update your information, we may keep a copy of your earlier information for our records.

If you do not want to receive e-mail or other communications from us, please indicate your choices in your Account Profile preferences Certain notifications, such as product changes or updated literature, or offers are only available electronically. Please note that even if you choose not to receive electronic communications from us, our terms and conditions and policies, such as Website Usage, Privacy Policy, and Terms and Condition of Sale or Samples, will still govern your use of our Sites, including any products you purchase or samples you request. It is your responsibility to review our policies and terms and conditions for any changes. If you do not accept our terms and conditions and policies, please do not use our Sites or their offerings.

You can avoid certain "cookies" by indicating in your Customer Profile that you do not want us to remember you. Your browser may also have options to prevent acceptance of new “cookies.” There are also utilities available allowing you to visit our Sites anonymously. Unfortunately, certain features and offerings available through the Sites may not be available to anonymous users.

Who does Microchip share Customer Information With?

Customer information is important for Microchip to be able to offer products and services to you. We are not in the business of selling customer information to others. We do share customer information with our subsidiaries and with others as described below. Such third parties may be based in the United States, Europe or Thailand. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties to whom your information may be transferred. If you do not wish us to share your information as described below, you may opt out by not supplying information to us when entering information into your Customer Profile, or by not placing orders through **[microchipdirect.com](http://www.microchipdirect.com/)**

Agents: We use other companies and persons to perform tasks on our behalf. Examples are not limited to delivering packages, processing credit card payments, checking for export compliance, and providing customer service. They have access to customer information to perform their jobs, but may not use it for other purposes. For example, if you make a purchase request through “microchipdirect”, or a sample request through "sample.microchip", Microchip will share your customer information with third parties and receive information from credit bureaus and other companies to help prevent and detect fraud, and to offer credit or financial services to some customers.

Distributors and Sales Representatives: These companies and persons often provide service to Microchip’s customers. They have access to customer information to perform their jobs, which is not limited to marketing Microchip products, but may not use it for other purposes.

Third Parties: Except for information transmitted to Microchip through the on-line support system at http://support.microchip.com, any other technical submissions to Microchip such as designs, ideas or data that you transmit to or post on our Sites by any means (the "Submissions") for any purpose including but not limited to contest participation is considered and treated by Microchip as nonconfidential and nonproprietary.

Conformance with the Law: We release account and other customer information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the laws of Arizona.

Protection of Microchip and Others: Microchip will release customer information necessary to enforce or apply our Website Terms of Use, and other agreements. Microchip will, at its discretion, release customer information necessary to protect the rights, property and safety of Microchip or others in accordance with the laws of Arizona.

Security

We use 256-bit encryption to secure the financial information you enter. Only the last five digits of your credit card number are listed in your Order Acknowledgement. However, your entire credit card number is transmitted to your credit card company during order processing, and your identifying and credit information is transmitted to companies that process your credit card transactions and review them for export control violations.

Law and Jurisdiction

Your visit to our Sites and any dispute over privacy is subject to our Privacy Policy and Website Terms of Use terms which include limitation on damages and application of the law of the state of Arizona, U.S.A without regard to any conflict of laws provisions. The federal and state courts of the state of Arizona shall have the exclusive jurisdiction to adjudicate any dispute relating to this Privacy Policy.

Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy and Website Terms of Use terms may change from time to time. Check our Sites frequently to see recent changes. We may notify you by e-mail of such changes (unless you have told us not to). Continued use of any of our Sites will signify that you agree to any such changes. Unless we expressly state otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information we have about you.

Consent

By submitting your information you consent to the use of that information as set out in this Privacy Policy.

Contact Us

If you have any concern about our treatment of your customer information, please send us an e-mail at [legal.department@microchip.com](mailto:legal.department@microchip.com).
